hey guys a while ago somebody mentioned
me in this video Let's Solve IT pause it
real quick if you want to try on your
own because I'm going to solve it now
this says the five semi-circles are
identical so we know they all have the
same radius and diameter it says solve
for the diameter so I'm going to label
each of these diameters as D I know that
the distance is the same whether I
measure from the top or the bottom so
I'm going to set those two things equal
to each other so we have triple d's plus
two twelves is going to be equal to
Double D's plus double 22s plus a single
16. well Double 12 is 24 and double 22
is 44 and then we can bring down
everything else let's combine like terms
the 44 and the 16 give us 60 and bring
down everything else subtract 2D from
both sides we get a single D plus 24
equals 60 and then subtract 24 from both
sides and we get D equals 60 minus 24
which is 36. let's squish these together
and put a box around it the diameter is
equal to 36. how exciting